[Apocalypse Log 4]
We were just strangers who met by chance.
Oh, forget it.
Lin Zai, you're awake.
I'll go heat up some food for you.
No need, Grandma.
I'll just have some biscuits.
- Chen.
- Yeah?
Where's Lie?
He's gone.
He's gone?
Why didn't you tell me?
Why tell you? Were you going to leave with him?
In this apocalypse, it's not easy
to find a reliable companion.
If he wasn't in such a hurry to leave,
it would have been great if he could stay.
Lin Zai, where are you going?
I'm going to bring Lie back.
Your wound hasn't healed yet.
Why are you running around?
You didn't leave?
What happened to you two?
Just bad luck.
We fell down a slope while gathering wood.
Luckily, it was a small one.
Otherwise, I'm not sure we would've
made it back today.
Oh, man.
My mouth is full of dirt.
Let's chat later. I need to go wash up.
Hey, what are you doing?
Put me down.
Put me down!
Hey, what's up with you two?
His wound opened up again.
How did that happen?
They just went to gather wood.
Why should an injured person tag along?
I thought...
I... I'm fine now.
It doesn't even hurt.
Hey, Lin Zai.
Wasn't your foot badly injured
a couple of days ago?
It's almost healed now.
Don't move.
Oh.
Maybe it just looked scary at the time.
Yeah.
It's good to be young. You're resilient.
Lie.
You should wash up, too.
I'll go right now.
Don't run about.
Immune target confirmed.
Laundry detergent.
The stains on your clothes...
Wash off as much as you can.
No need.
I've already dried them.
All right then.
You never seem to get any proper rest.
You're always so vigilant.
Aren't you tired?
I'm used to it.
Lie.
What did you work as before all this?
I have nothing to say about the past.
You said you still had important things to do.
What's that about?
That's not for you to ask.
I thought we were already friends.
I just wanted to know you better.
I'm going to catch a couple of fish.
We'll have an extra dish tonight.
Give me your hand.
A gift for you.
Lie.
The apocalypse has taken a lot from me.
So, I want to cherish the people I meet,
people I can rely on.
I think you're very trustworthy.
I think we could become
companions who are like family.
I don't know what it is
that you're risking your life for.
Maybe we can help you.
That way, you won't have to struggle alone,
or get hurt so much.
So... won't you stay?
No one can help me.
I won't be staying.
I understand.
When do you plan to leave?
Once your foot is healed, I'll leave.
Actually, you don't need to worry about me.
I'm almost fully recovered.
Look.
I'm not even using the crutch anymore.
Then I'll leave tomorrow.
Are you really not staying?
You've made up your mind?
Those meant to stay will stay,
and those who want to leave
cannot be forced to stay.
It's enough that we met.
All good things must come to an end.
Lie.
Wherever you go,
take good care of yourself, okay?
Thank you.
Buddy.
I really don't want you to go.
If you stay here, we'll feel so much safer.
Since you've already decided,
I won't say anything more.
We're parting ways tomorrow.
Let's treat this meal
as a farewell party for Lie.
Let's drink until we drop tonight.
Come on, bro.
Fill it up.
Come on.
Your foot hasn't healed yet.
You shouldn't drink.
It's fine.
Didn't you see my injury today?
Besides...
Since we've met,
I have to have a drink.
Since you've put it that way...
Fill it up.
Come on.
I hope we'll meet again one day.
I hope every one of you stays safe and well.
I hope the zombie crisis ends soon.
I hope...
I hope everyone's wishes come true.
Cheers.
Lie.
The apocalypse has taken a lot from me.
So, I want to cherish the people I meet,
the people I can rely on.
I think you're very trustworthy.
So... won't you stay?